JOHN KELLY

CONTACT

Address: Cheltenham Gloucestershire

GL54 5LJ

Phone: 07494371641

Email: jd.kelly803@gmail.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/j

ohnkelly803/

WEBSITES, PORTFOLIOS, PROFILES

https://waltzingintryst.netlify.app/

SKILLS

- Operating System: Windows (10, 11, Server 16, 19), Mac (Sierra, High Sierra, Mojave, Sonoma), Linux (Ubuntu, RHEL, Centos, Fedora, Nix)
- Endpoint Security: (Crowdstrike, MS Defender, Sentinel, Sophos, Meraki)
- O365: (Sharepoint, Teams, OneDrive, PowerBI, Office Suite, O365 Admin)
- Networking: (Azure & AWS SDN, LAN, WAN, TCP/IP, WiFi)
- Azure: (Entra ID (AZAD), Intune, Dynamic Grouping, MFA, Azure Services)
- Patch & assets Management: (Heimdal, Connectwise, Jamf, SolarWinds)
- 3rd party S/w: (Adobe, Egress, Figma, Miro, Axure, Apple Business Manager, Egnyte, Chrome browser Management)
- Scripting: (PowerShell, Python, Bash)
- · CICD: (Jenkins)
- Containerization (Docker)
- IaC: (Terraform, Ansible)
- Effective communication
- · Training and Development
- Software diagnostics
- IT troubleshooting
- Career Mentoring
- Supportive leadership within IT team

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Seasoned IT Engineer with 20+ years of experience spanning Windows, Mac, Linux, Azure, O365, Intune, Teams, virtualisation platforms, and popular security solutions. Consistently ensured peak performance, implemented rigorous security protocols, and maximized user satisfaction across multiple sites. Played a pivotal role in preparing infrastructures and companies for ISO certification. Ensured corporate devices and infrastructure are robust and reliable. By working closely with Information Security, maintained stringent documentation and regular reviews, underpinning the trust our clients place in our technology solutions.

WORK HISTORY

Self Development, 09/2023 to Current **NA** - Winchcombe, Gloucestershire

Having spent most of my career working within Windows environments, I decided to take some time out to educate myself on tools designed for DevOps in order to bring such knowledge to a future Operations role where by such tools can be utilized, bringing better automation and efficiency to the organization. I focused on learning Linux-based operating systems, containerization using Docker, and orchestration with Kubernetes. Additionally, I delved into the world of Infrastructure as Code (IaC) using Terraform & Ansible, enabling me to manage and provision End point devices & infrastructure resources more effectively. By acquiring this expertise, I am confident that I can make a significant impact in my future Operations role, streamlining processes and improving overall system reliability.

IT Operations Manager, 11/2019 to 09/2023 **Arkk Solutions** - City of London, London

- Upgraded hardware and software regularly for optimized systems performance, via Heimdal
- Managed Windows 10/11, Windows Server 16/19, Mac & iOS.
- Managed EntralD, Azure Sentinel, Intune, Defender Endpoint, Crowdstrike, Zscaler, O365, & Jamf
- Used PowerShell for Automation
- Setup & maintained asset management of entire technological landscape
- Installed new technologies without disrupting workflow.
- Maintained system security through regular testing and servicing.
- Managed technology resources within department budgets.
- Analyzed system and software requirements to meet operational needs.
- Assessed system performance to advise on possible updates and improvements.
- Advised on Information and communications technology policy and process improvements.
- Negotiated cost-efficient prices with vendors for new systems and services.
- Controlled department budgets by sourcing cost-effective solutions.

- Liaised with service users to ascertain necessary system improvements.
- Liaised with service users and business managers to meet computing requirements
- Sourced new and emerging technologies to optimize information services
- Engaged with external stakeholders, interpreting briefs to develop IT systems within allocated budget.
- Conducted in-depth research into diverse topics to create richlydetailed, factual works.
- Prepared easily understood, clear and complete user manuals and quides for consumers.
- Maintained version history for projects and organised file system.

Onsite IT Engineer, 03/2019 to 11/2019 **Netstar MSP** - City of London, City of London

- Tracked computer system and network performance to identify root causes of issues.
- Provided prompt support to internal and customer-facing IT infrastructure.
- Installed, configured and maintained high-performing multiplatform technologies.
- Resolved technical faults across varied technologies, including servers, routers and hardware.
- Carried out new hardware installations and updates, keeping systems functional and secure.
- Answered user questions about hardware and software operation to help resolve problems.
- Delivered reliable, high quality technical support to average of 100 users daily.
- Managed and implemented all new software, systems and solutions.
- Installed new software for users and monitored version and patch update requirements.
- Followed technical documentation for accurate installation, maintenance and repair work.
- Established and troubleshot network and data communications systems.
- Investigated, diagnosed and remedied diverse hardware issues within fixed service-level agreements.
- Organised workspaces for employees with computer, monitors and associated cabling or equipment.
- Developed robust patching regime for optimum server, storage, network and desktop environments.
- Distilled complex technical information into easily digestible instructions for end-users.

Lead Support Engineer, 02/2017 to 03/2019 **Dolfin Financial Group** - City of London, City of London

- Installed new software for users and monitored version and patch update requirements.
- Followed technical documentation for accurate installation, maintenance and repair work.
- Answered user questions about hardware and software operation to help resolve problems.
- Carried out new hardware installations and updates, keeping systems functional and secure.
- Prepared equipment for staff use, installing cables, operating systems, and software.
- Tracked computer system and network performance to identify root causes of issues.

- Maintained internet and intranet websites to maximize reliability and usability.
- Used Jira to track support tickets and document actions.
- Offered technical advice to programmers and developers to help optimize designs.
- Distilled complex technical information into easily digestible instructions for end-users.
- Organized workspaces for employees with computer, monitors and associated cabling or equipment.
- Mentored junior engineers, identifying skill gaps, and working towards their career goals

IT Support Engineer, 02/2015 to 02/2017 **Westgroup Investments Limited** - City of London, City of London

- Carried out new hardware installations and updates, keeping systems functional and secure.
- Installed new software for users and monitored version and patch update requirements.
- Monitored and performed hardware and software upgrades to network servers, including operating systems and applications.
- Troubleshot network issues and provided rapid solutions to limit downtime.
- Answered user questions about hardware and software operation to help resolve problems.
- Configured routers, switches and firewalls to deploy and support LAN, WAN and wireless networks.
- Prepared equipment for staff use, installing cables, operating systems, and software.

Head Bartender, 08/2013 to 01/2015 Ain't Nothin' But Blues Bar - London, London

- Performed bar closing duties, thoroughly cleaning, sanitising and replenishing stock.
- Oversaw bar recordkeeping and stocktaking for organised and profitable operations.
- Provided efficient food and drinks service for high levels of customer satisfaction.
- Collected cash payments, processing and providing correct change and receipts using Point Of Sale (POS) systems.
- Engaged with guests to create positive rapport, encouraging loyalty and repeat visits.
- Served guests spirits, lagers and stouts at bar.
- Maintained bar stocks, replenishing daily as necessary.
- Set up bar area daily with clean furniture, supplies and beverage stock for typical bar demands.
- Prepared mixed drinks and poured wine, beer and non-alcoholic beverages within target service timeframes.
- Maintained knowledge of drinks promotions, pricing and menu changes, offering customers up-to-date, reliable advice.
- Created range of alcoholic and non-alcoholic mixed drinks for establishment guests.
- Retained in-depth bar and menu item knowledge, providing expert recommendations to suit guest taste.
- Coordinated daily replenishment and stock resets to maintain organised, tidy bar space.
- Prepared for closing by cleaning bar area and announcing last orders.
- Created friendly, welcoming atmosphere to encourage positive guest experiences, prolonging visits to increase profitability.

Cyber Cafe Administrator, 11/2012 to 04/2013 **E-Lounge Cyber Cafe** - Melbourne, Australia

- Primary contact point for clients to identify problems and provide solutions and technical support.
- · Performed installations and updates.
- Maintenance of all pc's and consoles.
- Responsible for collecting cash drawers and end of shift reports.
- Responsible for the purchasing of Console Cards and refreshments.
- Maintained VIP Gamers Area.
- Maintained membership card systems and loyalty system.

IT Support, 05/2012 to 11/2012 Dodo Australia - Melbourne, Australia

- Gather customer's information and determine the issue by evaluating and analyzing the symptoms.
- Diagnose and resolve technical hardware and software issues involving internet connectivity, email clients, IPTV, VOIP and more.
- Working within a TCP/IP network environment, including DHCP, DNS, Router & Switch (Cisco) Configurations.
- Configured and maintained Office 365.
- Troubleshoot Exchange 2012 (such as, adding addresses to safe list and creating new accounts).
- Troubleshooting of Windows (Win Vista and Win 7), and Mac Environments (Mountain Lion and Yosemite)
- Worked heavily with Windows Server 2012 and Active Directory.

IT Support & Interstate Driver, 05/2011 to 12/2011 **Fast Move** - Melbourne, Australia

- Maintained a wide range of computer hardware, Including Dell Workstations and Laptops.
- Kept detailed logs and documentations on all hardware and software.
- Diagnosed connectivity, hardware and software issues.
- Configured and maintained Windows Server 2003 and Gmail accounts.
- Installed, configured and maintained GPS equipment on all company vehicles.
- Installed and maintained CCTV systems for both property and Vehicle

Information Services Support Technician, 07/2006 to 04/2011 Benton Property Holdings - Dublin, Ireland

- Ensuring phones and internet were connected for each new client.
- Investigate specialist and complex IT support issues.
- Maintenance and security of workstations within Benton Head Office and Group subsidiary companies to ensure maximum efficiency and up-time.
- Developing the infrastructure and systems to meet the company's needs.
- Working within a TCP/IP network environment, including DHCP, & DNS.
- Configuring and managing backup & restore procedures.
- Creating ID cards and fobs for both commercial and residential tenants.
- Maintaining a wide range of computer hardware and software.
- Identifying & reporting on the budgetary implications of IT projects and upgrades.
- Provide secondary support for LAN administration and Video Conferencing (Polycom).
- Documentation of all activity relating to system configurations, modifications and installations.
- Liaise with contractors in relation to office appliance, security and

electrical installations.

• Protecting the security of all systems within the Benton Group of companies and compliance with Data Protection and other legislation.

EDUCATION

 $\mbox{\bf RHCSA}:$ Red hat Certified Systems administration, 05/2024 - Current

At Home - Winchcombe

DevOps Bootcamp: DevOps Bootcamp, 09/2023 - Current **Tech World with Nana** - At home

HOBBIES AND INTEREST

- Tinkering with Linux & python
- Working at charity farm for kids with special needs
- Workingout

REFERENCES

References available upon request.